Guide to the Stanley Milgram Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, 1950-1993; Accession 2016-M-086
  - Film: The City and the Self
    - From, Harry, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Expenses (From), 1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Harry From, memoranda and correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Time-Life, 1973-1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Distribution, sales, etc., 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Conformity in Norway and France: An Experimental Study of National Characteristics, dissertation, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Milgram's Obedience Paradigm 30 Years Later: Where Do We Go From Here?, American Psychological Association, Toronto, Canada, August 20, 1993 meeting, 1993 December 15 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Milgram student papers, correspondence, press releases, etc., 1950-1955 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
  - "Remembering Stanley Milgram" letters, articles, and photographs, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Binder with notes on psychology, autobiography, and personal goals, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Unidentified audiocassette, Undated; 1 (Box 3)
- Additional Material, 1948-1986; Accession 2017-M-0032; 18.06; (25 boxes)
  The papers are open for research.
  The accession contains material related to Milgram's psychology experiments and research. Materials from Milgram's teachings at Yale University include photographs of his obedience experiment laboratory and office files. Also in the accession are materials relating to Milgram's experiments while at the City University of New York, including 15 reels of 16mm film, 5 cassette tapes, and photographs from his study of Paris, France. Additionally, the collection includes correspondence and writings, both professional and personal, from Milgram as a student and young man studying at Princeton and working in the United States, Norway, Denmark, and France.
  The material is arranged into three groupings: audiovisual material, photographs, and office and research files.
  - Audiovisual material
    - City narration
      - Web of City Life- music track, Circa 1975; 1 (Box 1)
      - Cassette tape, Circa 1970s; 1 (Box 2)
      - Cassette tape, Circa 1970s; 1 (Box 3)
      - Cassette tape, Circa 1970s; 1 (Box 4)
      - Cassette tape, Circa 1970s; 1 (Box 5)
    - Paris/New York City study
      - Film reel, 1979-07-24; 1 (Box 6)
      - Film reel, 1979-07-24; 1 (Box 7)
      - Film reel, 1979-07-24; 1 (Box 8)
      - Film reel, 1979-07-24; 1 (Box 9)
      - Film reel, 1979-07-24; 1 (Box 10)
      - Film reel, 1979-07-24; 1 (Box 11)
      - Film reel, 1979-07-24; 1 (Box 12)
      - Film reel, 1979-07-24; 1 (Box 13)
      - Film reel, 1979-07-24; 1 (Box 14)
      - Film reel, 1979-07-24; 1 (Box 15)
      - Film reel, 1979-07-24; 1 (Box 16)
      - Film reel, Circa 1970s; 1 (Box 17)
      - Film reel, Circa 1970s; 1 (Box 18)
      - Film reel, Circa 1970s; 1 (Box 19)
      - Two Worlds at Play: Hasidic and Hispanic, Circa 1970s; 1 (Box 20)
    - Photographic slides, 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 1-13)
  - Photographs
    - Studies, 1975-1980 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Notes from television and antisocial experiment, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Aggression and non-verbal behavior production stills, 1970s (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Photographs and television violence, 1970s (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Mental maps, Paris, 1970s (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Paris original negatives, 1970s (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Obedience study, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 7-8)
    - W.R. Grace Building design, Circa 1970 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Photography - illustrations by J. A. W., 1970s (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Paris street maps, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Stanley Milgram portrait, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Negatives for TV report, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Paris
      - Boulevard Saint-Germain, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Rue de la Harpe, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Café de Flore, Saint Germain, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Square Willette, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Rue du Chevalier de la Barre, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Monument aux morts, Gare St. Lazare, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - La Goutte d'or, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Montparnasse, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Rue de Chartres, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - Paris dangereux, Goutte d'or, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Square Montsouris, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - Latin Quarter, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - Avenue Victor Hugo, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 16)
      - Saint Germain, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 17)
      - Île Saint-Louis, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 18)
      - Rue de la Glacière, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 19)
      - Square Willette, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 20)
      - Montmartre, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 21)
      - Parvis Notre-Dame, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 22)
      - Rue Marcadet, Circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Office and research files
    - New York University Film Library - City and the Self, 1982-1986 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Little, Brown and Company reader correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Harper and Row
      - Obedience correspondence, 1969-1972 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Films correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Obedience correspondence, paperback, 1975-1980 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Creative writing while at Princeton, 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Random notes, papers, ideas, creative writing (poems and stories), 1951-1960 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Long Day accounts, Cambridge, Paris, Princeton, 1958-1959 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Writings and ideas, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Personal correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Personal correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Writings and thoughts on Oslo, Norway, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Personal writing, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Notes on the Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton, New Jersey, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Albert, Dr. Stuart, recommendation, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Selective Service correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Writings and thoughts on Norway, Denmark, and France, Circa 1950s (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Antony research, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Harvard letters, reviews - Allport, Bruner, Kelman, 1956-1960 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Personal correspondence, 1950-1954 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Personal correspondence, 1954-1960 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Writings and ideas, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Allport, Gordon W., correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1960 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence - Europe, 1953-1958 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Obedience study - original data, Circa 1961 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Yale appointments, 1963-1968 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Psychology Today lecture, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Program Corporation of America, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Program Corporation of America - Chataqua and taxes, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - New York University Film Library - contract and correspondence, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - New York University Film Library - obedience correspondence, 1971-1981 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Film: candy store idea, 1970s (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Films: Urban Dogs and other films, 1970s (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Record of ideas, 1970s (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Thank you letter, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Family Christmas letter, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Medical, 1975-1980 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Family Christmas letter, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Know Your Personality, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950-1984 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Data on line study, 1970s (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Peyote, mescalin, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Children and nuclear war, 1970s (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Obedience book responses to contribution, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Film: Paris, New York, 1970s (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - New York and Paris mental map, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Awards, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Instructions for the use of Esterline Angus graphic recording instrument, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Research foundation bills and payments - purchase orders, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Research foundation correspondence, phone number, 1983-1984 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Young cyronoids - signed consent forms, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 27)